It's cold!
Did you see that, Ioryogi!?
Huh? What?
I'll try it again!
Look, it's great!
Yeah, that's winter for you.
It's great!
Yeah, definitely winter.
How about that? You warm enough now?
You're terrible...
What shall I do?
Even the obvious things are always so hard
I just want to grin when I'm happy, sing when I'm in love
They say my dreams will come true someday
but when will someday come? I can't wait!
Count one, two, three and spread my arms
Gather the light to myself
Where is it? Tell me what I can do
Even if I'm hurt so much, even if I run so hard
Even if I collapse crying over and over, I still
believe in my amazing future
... Warmth in a Chill Wind.
Hey, Kobato.
What, Ioryogi?
What comes after winter?
Spring!
That's right. You know it's almost spring, right?
You've got until spring to fill this bottle with candy.
Yeah.
If you don't hurry, you're not going to be able to go anywhere.
Yeah...
My silly dad this morning had his tummy sticking out!
Really?
My big brother-
What's wrong?
That man's out there again...
Come on.
Let's just go home for today.
Mommy?
I'm gonna call the cops.
I haven't come in. You don't have anything to complain about.
This is harassment.
I'm just standing here.
I sure would be worried sending my kids to a nursery like this.
Fujimoto?
It's him.
That loan shark again.
Let's go.
But...
Ignore him.
Hello, this is Yomogi Nursery.
Rikako's mother?
I was worried when she didn't come today.
Well, that's...
Understood. Just send over the paperwork.
Of course.
Yes, that will be fine.
Tell Rikako goodbye for me.
Rikako's quitting.
She's the third one this month.
This is getting to the families.
Quit making excuses. I told you to deal with it yourself.
Wow, there's so many!
Thanks, Domoto.
Don't worry about it. I had plenty left over.
Thanks. Now we'll be able to have a fun Christmas party.
This one's great! I want to hang it up!
Miss Sayaka?
Don't overdo it.
I'm fine.
Anyway...
Fujimoto and Kobato are on the roof.
Thanks.
Miss Sayaka seems so lonesome.
She's just as kind as normal, but...
So, so lonesome...
Yeah.
That man...
And that as soon as time's up, she's getting shut down.
No way!
I don't care if there's kids around.
If you don't want someone to get hurt, you'd better clear out.
Why is he doing something so mean?
Okiura is Miss Sayaka's husband, isn't he?
Like that means anything.
I... I'm going to try talking with him!
What?
Don't!
But we can't just have that man out there!
He's not someone you can talk things over with.
If I try talking to him, I think he'll understand!
I told you, don't!
Why not?
Stay out of it, okay?
But Miss Sayaka will be said if anyone else quits!
That's nothing for you to worry about!
Don't do anything, okay!?
But-!
Domoto?
What's wrong?
Did something happen?
She's the third one this month.
This is getting to the families.
I see.
If I don't do something...
If there was anything that could be done, I'm sure Kiyokazu would already have tried.
I know how you feel, but you really shouldn't do anything.
But maybe if I beg him!
But...
If this keeps up, Yomogi Nursery won't be here anymore.
Everyone will be sad. So I've got to go and talk with him!
Kobato!
Snow! Let's put snow all over!
That would be wonderful.
White snow everywhere.
Mister Kiyokazu!
Let's hang this up!
We can put a little snowman in the middle!
Huh? What's Dobato up to now?
Who're you?
I'm Hanato Kobato!
Great weather, isn't it?
It feels so good lying in a nice soft bed on days like today.
Playing, then a soft nap, saying "see you tomorrow" and then all coming back to Yomogi Nursery tomorrow.
What are you going on about?
We went on a field trip!
And made pictures from leaves!
Digging for sweet potatoes was fun, too!
So many people came to the bazaar we just had!
Everyone has such fond memories of this nursery!
So please don't shut down Yomogi Nursery!
Please!
You've gotta pay up first.
I know.
Let us pay bit by bit!
Kobato, even if you talk to him...
What's wrong?
Nothing!
He's right. Talking to me about it won't change anything.
Then I'll talk with Okiura.
He isn't gonna wanna hear it.
Even if he did, there's no way his old man is gonna show any pity.
His old man?
I'm leaving, but I'll be back!
Please! Don't-
Later!
Kobato, you should give up for today.
Okay...
Are you okay!?
Does your stomach hurt?
Back off!
But-!
Shut up! Leave me alone!
I can't just ignore you!
Are you okay!?
What's wrong!? Are you okay!?
Huh, that's Kobato.
Takashi's with her.
He suddenly collapsed!
Kobato's gone...
Miss Sayaka?
The ambulance went whoo-whoo...
That's right.
All right, let's get some sleep.
Hello, Yomogi Nursery.
Appendicitis?
I see.
Yeah. I'll tell Miss Sayaka.
Kobato?
The operation's over. He should be fine now.
Really?
Yeah. They said not to worry.
I see...
Let's go.
Okay.
Oh?
What's up?
That man you sent to stand out front.
He had appendicitis.
Appendicitis?
He's as Chuo Hospital. The surgery went fine.
I see. Did I trouble you?
Yeah.
Then why not just leave? You're not going to be able to pay me back.
You know that, right?
Can't we talk it over?
Talk it over?
What's so funny!?
What's wrong? This isn't like you.
Just tell me whether we can!
No way.
Anyway, thanks for telling me about that.
Oh, by the way.
What!?
You should give up and move on, Kiyo.
Why did I even call him?
If I try talking to him, I think he'll understand!
We're back.
Oh.
He's okay. He should be back on his feet soon.
I see.
Bye-bye, Kobato!
Bye-bye!
Mom! Rikako quit!
Oh really?
That's enough for today, Kobato.
But there's still cleaning to do.
Today was a busy day. Go home and get some rest.
We'll be busy setting up for the Christmas party tomorrow, remember?
Okay...
Let's leave it for later.
Domoto.
Thanks for helping out today.
It's nothing.
I'll go get my bag.
Sorry to keep you waiting, Ioryogi.
Not even one more candy today. What are you doing?
But at least that man will be healthy again soon. Isn't that nice?
That's no excuse! When he gets better he'll just come back!
C'mon, you're-
What's wrong?
Fujimoto was mad...
He told me not to do anything, but I...
You didn't do anything wrong, Kobato. Don't worry about it.
But...
Mind if I sit down, Kobato?
What should I do?
Without Yomogi Nursery, everyone will be sad.
What can I do?
Kobato...
You always worry about the people around you, don't you.
You're kind, direct, and always enthusiastic.
Kobato...
I like girls like you.
Thank you, Domoto!
That really cheered me up!
You're welcome.
Here.
It's so warm!
Thanks!
Kobato...
Yes? What is it?
Do you... Do you want to spend Christmas together?
Kiyokazu?
Did you just get home?
Yeah.
Oh. Tell me if you need anything else for the Christmas party.
Fine.
Thanks for lending me your muffler!
See you later!
Later.
See you.
Sure.
People all want to fly
but they're cheated by gravity
everyone can really fly
She must be so unhappy because
she forgot her own shadow somewhere
Then...
If you tell me "thanks", if you say "thanks" and smile
Going back and forth, we'll be happy
You'll be happy, there'll be nothing to worry about
As long as we're together
It's strange, I'm crying even though I'm happy
... White Christmas.
Next episode